<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>learning on Liberatys - Nick</title>
    <link>https://liberatnick.ch/tags/learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in learning on Liberatys - Nick</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 08:35:33 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://liberatnick.ch/tags/learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>CSS</title>
      <link>https://liberatnick.ch/post/internship_css/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 08:35:33 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://liberatnick.ch/post/internship_css/</guid>
      <description>This blog entry has been created after going through the Learn css in Y Minutes course. I&amp;rsquo;ve taken the liberty to take some examples they provide on their webiste. To learn more please visit the link above.
CSS Web pages are buillt and structured with HTML, which specifies the content and hirachy of a page. CSS(Cascading Styles Sheets) specifies the apperance of a page.
CSS is a set of static rules that define how an object appears on the page based on its selectors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SASS</title>
      <link>https://liberatnick.ch/post/internship_sass/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 08:35:33 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://liberatnick.ch/post/internship_sass/</guid>
      <description>This blog entry has been created after going through the Learn sass in Y Minutes course. I&amp;rsquo;ve taken the liberty to take some examples they provide on their webiste. To learn more please visit the link above.
SASS Sass is an extension to the css language. It tries to bring some features to css that will make larger codebases easier and will also help developers keep track of current colors and other variables that are the same all across the board.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MVC</title>
      <link>https://liberatnick.ch/post/internship_mvc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 13:45:28 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://liberatnick.ch/post/internship_mvc/</guid>
      <description>A small entry about the MVC design pattern</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ruby</title>
      <link>https://liberatnick.ch/post/internship_ruby/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 18:53:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://liberatnick.ch/post/internship_ruby/</guid>
      <description>Ruby Today we had the opportunity to go through a tutorial / course on the ruby programming language. Because Ruby on Rails is a wiedly adopted tool in the field of web development, ruby and the knowledge thereof can come in handy in many situations.
Difference between Ruby and other langauges  Ruby is a very dynamic and adaptive programming language that enables the programmer to go fast and stay close to the meaning of what he is trying to achieve Most methods and operations in ruby are intutive and very close to spoken language(English) Ruby code is compact, elegant and brings along a lot of hidden magic Ruby is an open source langauge.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
