<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Liberatys - Nick</title>
    <link>https://liberatnick.ch/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Liberatys - Nick</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2021 16:52:44 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://liberatnick.ch/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Vimtex and Zathura on Arch / Manjaro (in NVIM)</title>
      <link>https://liberatnick.ch/posts/vimtex_and_zathura_on_manjaro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2021 16:52:44 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://liberatnick.ch/posts/vimtex_and_zathura_on_manjaro/</guid>
      <description>Installing Vimtext with Zathura on Manjaro / Arch Linux A short introduction to installing vimtex and zathura on linux (arch / manjaro).
Installations First, you should install zathura on your system
I usually install packages from the integrated package manager but you are free to install them from the source.
 sudo pacman -S zathura  To use vimtex we also need latexmk which is usually packaged inside the bigger latex utilities and applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why [Neovim|Vim] might not be my forever editor</title>
      <link>https://liberatnick.ch/posts/why_neovim_might_not_be_my_forever_editor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 21:45:34 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://liberatnick.ch/posts/why_neovim_might_not_be_my_forever_editor/</guid>
      <description>A relationship with an expiration date? I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Neovim(and Vim before that) for about three years now. A teacher of mine told me to play the vim adventure game so that I had something to do in class. It was not love at first sight.
And for many reasons:
 There were no fancy images / emojis No refactoring tools It was running on the terminal Strange keybindings Modes? Why can&amp;rsquo;t I just insert characters in normal mode?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qutebrowser</title>
      <link>https://liberatnick.ch/posts/qutebrowser/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2020 22:26:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://liberatnick.ch/posts/qutebrowser/</guid>
      <description>Why I think that we should all ban our mouse from the workflow.
Qutebrowser
Qutebrowser ? What is that The qutebrowser is a very cool browser that has been around for some time. What is different about qutebrowser and separates it from other browsers, is that it is mostly driven by keybindings and your beloved vim keys.
For instance, I do not have to move my mouse from the page to the status bar in order to insert a new url.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git Flow</title>
      <link>https://liberatnick.ch/posts/git_flow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://liberatnick.ch/posts/git_flow/</guid>
      <description>References:
 https://danielkummer.github.io/git-flow-cheatsheet/ https://nvie.com/posts/a-successful-git-branching-model/  Git flow is multiple things. On the one side it&amp;rsquo;s a git extension that you can use to push, pull, merge and checkout. On the other side its a branching model that gives you advice on handling your branching system in git repos.
First I&amp;rsquo;d like to show the git extensions so that we have that out of the way
Installation of Git Extensions MacOS Homebrew brew install git-flow-avh Macports port install git-flow-avh Linux apt-get install git-flow Windows Cygwin wget -q -O - --no-check-certificate https://raw.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSS</title>
      <link>https://liberatnick.ch/posts/internship_css/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 08:35:33 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://liberatnick.ch/posts/internship_css/</guid>
      <description>This blog entry has been created after going through the Learn css in Y Minutes course. I&amp;rsquo;ve taken the liberty to take some examples they provide on their webiste. To learn more please visit the link above.
CSS Web pages are buillt and structured with HTML, which specifies the content and hirachy of a page. CSS(Cascading Styles Sheets) specifies the apperance of a page.
CSS is a set of static rules that define how an object appears on the page based on its selectors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SASS</title>
      <link>https://liberatnick.ch/posts/internship_sass/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 08:35:33 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://liberatnick.ch/posts/internship_sass/</guid>
      <description>This blog entry has been created after going through the Learn sass in Y Minutes course. I&amp;rsquo;ve taken the liberty to take some examples they provide on their webiste. To learn more please visit the link above.
SASS Sass is an extension to the css language. It tries to bring some features to css that will make larger codebases easier and will also help developers keep track of current colors and other variables that are the same all across the board.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MVC</title>
      <link>https://liberatnick.ch/posts/internship_mvc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 13:45:28 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://liberatnick.ch/posts/internship_mvc/</guid>
      <description>A small entry about the MVC design pattern</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ruby</title>
      <link>https://liberatnick.ch/posts/internship_ruby/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 18:53:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://liberatnick.ch/posts/internship_ruby/</guid>
      <description>Ruby Today we had the opportunity to go through a tutorial / course on the ruby programming language. Because Ruby on Rails is a wiedly adopted tool in the field of web development, ruby and the knowledge thereof can come in handy in many situations.
Difference between Ruby and other langauges  Ruby is a very dynamic and adaptive programming language that enables the programmer to go fast and stay close to the meaning of what he is trying to achieve Most methods and operations in ruby are intutive and very close to spoken language(English) Ruby code is compact, elegant and brings along a lot of hidden magic Ruby is an open source langauge.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
